# 한글화 : 태름아버지(200701) #
06, 12, 29, 유명을 달리하신
시네스트 도체님께 이 자막을 바칩니다.
▶◀ 삼가 고인의 명복을 빕니다 ▶◀
제길! 오!
Damn it! Oh!
아!
Ah!
제스!
Jes!
못참겠어,
도와줘!
I can't stand it, help me!
Help me!
제길!
God damn!
이런...
God...
제길!
damn!
나오려고 하는데,
자, 이제, 힘줘,
It's wanting out,
now darn it, push,
그래야 뭐가 나오려는지
볼 수 있지.
so we can see
what's coming out on the couch.
머리는 거의 다 나왔어.
Head's out almost.
빌어먹을!
God damn!
이런! 오...
Oh, God! Oh...
쉬~~.
Shh.
어서.
Come on.
자기야, 어서.
Oh, baby, come on.
오!
Oh!
- 걱정말아요, 찾아 볼테니까.
- 엄마가 아기를 낳았어요!
Don't worry, baby,
I'll get somebody.
Mama had the baby!
이리와, 조세핀,
우리 둘 다 오래.
Come on, Josephine,
he wants two of us.
못가.
바쁘다구.
I can't.
I'm busy.
아그네스를 데려가.
Get Agnes.
엄마가 아기를 낳았어요!
아들이예요!
Mama had the baby!
It's a boy!
아들?
A boy?
제길!
God damn.
내기에 졌잖아.
I lost my bet.
이봐,
이미 2 명 요금을 냈잖아,
Listen,
I've already paid for two,
난 준비됐다구.
I'm ready now.
아무렴요, 자기는,
Sure you are, sweetie,
좋은 애를 데리고 올거예요.
and we're going
to get someone nice.
바이올렛!
Violet!
끝내주는 시간을
가질 거니까요!
'Cause we're going
to have ourselves a time!
가서 아그네스 좀 데려와,
알았지, 예쁜아?
Go and fetch Agnes yonder,
will you, baby?
블루 룸으로 빨리 오라고 해.
Tell her to haul it up
to the Blue Room.
정말 황홀한 시간이 될거예요.
We're going to have ourselves
a time.
아들이야.
It's a boy.
아들을 낳았어.
다 큰아가씨, 바이올렛,
윗층은 다 끝났어?
Well, Violet, old girl,
is it all over upstairs?
어-허.
Uh-huh.
아들이야.
A boy.
아들?
A boy?
아기를 낳을 때
정말 많이 아파?
Does it really hurt
to have a baby?
바이올렛,
물어 볼 사람에게 물어야지,
Violet, you asking
the wrongest person,
세상에서 제일
부적절한 사람에게 묻다니.
the very wrongest person
in the world.
그것 좀 연주해 봐요, 교수님.
Come on and play
that thing, Professor.
음, 확실하게 연주해 드리죠.
Well, I certainly
will do that.
네 엄마가 방금 낳은
프리티 베이비에에 바치는 곡이야.
I'll play something for that
pretty baby your mama just had.
오늘 같은 밤, 무정하고,
잔혹한 세상에 태어난,
Brung into the cruel, cruel
world on a night like this,
자기 의지와는 상관없이 말야.
against his will.
오늘은 내 75 살 생일인데,
자축을 할 생각이야!
And today, I have attained
my 75th birthday, and
I intend to celebrate!
나랑 오랫 동안
얘기를 할 여자가 없어.
I haven't had a woman
in longer than I care to say.
예쁠 필요도 없고,
You know, she doesn't
have to be beautiful,
참을성만 있으면 돼.
just patient.
프리다는 어떠세요?
Well, how about Frieda?
안녕하세요, 장군님?
How are you, Admiral?
안녕, 넬.
Well, hello, Nell.
북해에 가셨었죠.
You've been to the North Sea.
그래요, 그리고 지금은
연장휴가 중이오.
I sure have, and now
I'm on an extended
leave of absence.
- 그리고, 난...
- 여기 오래 계실 거라구요.
- Well, I'm...
- Going to be here a long time.
우, 내가 좋아하는 타입 남자세요.
Ooh, you're my kind of man.
춤추시는게 마음에 들어요.
I like the way
you move.
네게 듣고싶은 말은, 내가
All I want to hear from you
멋지고, 씩씩하고, 통이 크고,
친절하다는 말 뿐이야.
is that I'm handsome,
virile, generous, and kind.
# 와플 사세요,
# 와플 사세요...
Waffle man, waffle man...
# 돈을 챙기세요,
# 와플이 왔어요.
Put your money in your hand
for the waffle man
# 와플사세요.
For the waffle man
# 와플이 왔어요,
# 와플이요.
The waffle man is here,
the waffle man is there
# 어디든 가는 와플 사세요,
The waffle man is everywhere
# 와플이오, 와플...
Waffle man, waffle man...
왜그래, 윌?
What's the matter, Will?
쉬~, 어서, 그쳐.
Shh, come on, hush up.
남들 다 깨우고 싶지 않잖아.
You don't want to wake
everybody up.
쉬~ !
이제 조용히 해.
Shh! Be quiet now.
바이올렛!
Violet!
저 사람을 깨웠으면
어쩔 뻔 했어?
What if you had woke him up?
하룻밤 요금을 냈단말야,
저 사람 성질 알잖아.
He paid for all night,
and you know what he's like.
윌 때문에 깼단 말예요.
Well, Will woke me up.
날 깨우지 말았어야지.
You're not supposed
to wake me up.
이젠 늦잠도 못자게 생겼네.
I don't get to sleep late
anymore.
그 귀걸이 어디서 났어?
Where'd you get those earrings?
엄청 예쁘다.
They're awful pretty.
어디서 났든 상관마.
Never mind where I got 'em.
그 사람이 줬어.
He gave 'em to me.
카드인지 뭔지 해서 땄대.
He won 'em in a card game
or something.
이제 내가
그 사람에게 딴거지.
Then I won them from him.
하지마!
Don't!
어제 밤에 뚷어 준거야,
Just pierced them
for me last night,
그 조건으로 내가 딴거라구.
that's how I won 'em.
다행히도 난 취해있었어.
It's a lucky thing I was drunk.
어른이 되면 내게 줄거야?
Will you give them
to me when I grow up?
너 제정신이니?
Are you
out of your mind?
이건 진짜 에메랄드야.
These are real emeralds.
그렇지 않았으면,
절대 그 사람에게
Otherwise,
I never would have let him
내 귀에 못생긴 구멍을
뚷게하지 않았을거야.
punch those ugly holes
in my ears.
커피줘.
컨디션이 엉망이야.
Get my coffee.
I feel awful.
# 우카, 두카, 소다, 크래커
Ooka, dooka, soda cracker,
# 네 아빠 담배 씹냐?
does your father chew tobacco?
- 우카...
- 바이올렛!
- Ooka...
- Violet!
내 지팡이 좀 다오.
Give me my cane.
오, 내 앱생트.
Oh, my absinthe.
빌어먹을 땀둥이 계집은
내 커피 가지러 어디로 간거야?!
Where the hell
is that black bitch
with my coffee?!
그거 조심해서 다뤄야해, 조.
Yes, you handle that
with care, Joe.
그 녀석에게 젖은
이제 그만 먹여야해.
And you ought to leave off
suckling that boy.
걔 버릇이 나빠진다구,
바이올렛 처럼.
You're going
to turn him spoiled,
just like you did with Violet.
내 보기엔, 지가 좋아하는 것 같아,
가슴이 커지니까.
Oh, I think she likes it,
having big tits.
헤이, 토냐, 바이올렛,
조랑말에서 내려와.
Hey, 'Tonia, Violet,
get off that pony.
니들에게 할 말이 있어.
I got something to tell you.
어제 밤에
마마 모스베리에게 갔는데.
I went to see Mama Mosebery
last night.
2 달러를 내니까, 행운을 가져올
요리 안한 거북이 심장을 줬어,
I paid her two dollars,
and she gave me some
uncooked turtle heart
to bring me luck
복권에 당첨되라고,
그냥 꿀꺽 삼켜버렸어!
for the lottery,
and I swallowed it whole!
어디가?
Where you going?
너 재밌게 해주자고
여기 온거 아냐.
I ain't here, you know,
to entertain you.
윗층에 배달하러 온 거라구.
I gots deliveries upstairs.
맛이 어땠어?
Well, how'd it taste like?
무슨 맛이 어때?
What taste like?
생 거북이 심장!
Raw turtle's heart!
맛이 어땠을 것 같냐?
What do you think
it tasted like?
아우, 제발, 말해줘!
Aw, come on, please, tell me!
난 거북이를 믈어뜯은 남자이야.
Well, I am the child
of a snapping turtle.
표범 젖을 먹고
악어로 길러졌지.
Raised by alligators
on panther's milk.
난 비터 크리크의
사나운 늑대야,
I'm a poisoned wolf
from Bitter Creek,
오늘밤은
내가 짖는 날이라구!
and tonight's
my night to howl!
행상은 뒷문으로 오세요.
Peddlers use the back door.
넷, 다섯, 여섯...
...four, five, six...
행상이예요.
A peddler.
바이올렛,
가서 오크라 마저 먹어.
Violet, go sit down
and finish your okra.
널 그렇게 안길렀는데,
아마 네 이빨은 썩게 될걸.
I'm not raising you so's
your teeth will rot, you know.
이 시트는 여기서 뭐하는거지?
What is this sheet
doing here?
이건 우리집 시트가 아니잖아.
It doesn't belong to the house.
여섯, 일곱, 어덟, 아홉...
Six, seven, eight, nine...
뭐가 왔나 봐요.
Look what's coming.
...eleven.
아우, 울지마,
착하지, 아가,
Aw, hush up now, come on, baby,
shh, shh, shh.
하이, 난 벨라크예요.
마담 리빙스턴을 찾아왔어요.
Hi, I'm Bellocq.
I'm looking
for Madame Livingston.
방문객을 맞으실까요?
Is she receiving callers?
해리, 이리 내려와.
Harry, get down here.
들어와요, 무슈 벨라크.
You may come in,
Monsieur Bellocq.
들어오세요.
Well, come in then.
이런, 잘못찾아 오셨수, 무슈.
Good God, you're in
the wrong place, Monsieur.
우린 물건을 사지 않아요.
We're not
in the business of buying.
마담, 제 이름을 아실거예요.
Madame, um,
perhaps you know my name.
전... 이 고장에서
사진을 많이 찍어왔거든요.
I have... photographed
in the district many times.
마담 리빙스턴이라 불러도 될까요?
Am I addressing
Madame Livingston?
네, 그러시구려,
무슈.
Yes, you are,
Monsieur.
너무 일찍 왔어요.
And you are too early.
아가씨들은 모두 자고있어요.
My girls are all asleep.
다들 늦게까지 일을 해서.
They work late, you know.
지금은 아침 10 시예요, 무슈.
It's 10:00 in the morning,
Monsieur.
전 햇볕이 필요하거든요.
I require the light
from the sun.
지금이 제겐
제일 좋은 시간이예요.
Now is the best time for me.
저기 있는 아가씨면,
This young lady there,
아주 좋을 것 같은데요.
she would be fine.
여긴 구식 창녀집이예요, 무슈.
I run a good, old-fashioned
whorehouse, Monsieur.
내가 보기에
당신은 좀 소심하네요.
And you seem
a little rabbity to me.
사진이라고?
Photographs?
그게 대체 뭐하는 물건이야?
What the hell
kind of thing is that?
난 변태들은 상대 안해.
I don't cater to the inverts.
색다른것을 찾는거라면,
If you're looking
for something different,
장담하건대, 찾을수 있을거요,
여기 뉴 올린스에서 말이오.
I can assure you,
you can find it
right down here
in New Orleans.
마담, 뉴 올린스 얘긴 마세요.
저도 여기서 평생을 살았어요.
Madame, please, don't tell me
about New Orleans,
I've lived here all my life.
사과하리다, 무슈.
I apologize, Monsieur.
기꺼이 요금도
낼거란 거 아실 거예요.
You realize I'm willing
to pay for her time.
바이올렛, 가서 레드가 가져온
꾸러미 가져오너라.
Violet, child, go get me
that package that Red brought.
앱생트 한 잔 하실라우?
Would you care
for an absinthe?
마담, 빛 말인데요.
Madame, the light.
뭐라구요?
I beg your pardon.
아, 햇빛.
Oh, the light.
깜빡했어요.
I had quite forgotten.
그럼, 해티를 데려가세요.
Well, go and take our Hattie.
아주 좋은 아가씨예요.
She's very good, you know.
당신이 원하면 뭐든 할거예요.
She will do whatever you want.
감사합니다, 마담.
Thank you, ma'am.
가서 아기 좀 봐주거라.
And go take care
of that child for her.
지금 옷을 벗을까요?
Want me
to take my clothes off now?
아니, 아녜요,
지금 이대로가 좋아요.
No, no, I'm liking you
just as you are.
이대로가 맘에든다구요?
You want me like this?
머리도 안빗고,
씼지도 않았는데.
Uncombed,
I'm not even washed.
네, 그럼요.
Yes, yes.
난 그 얼굴 맘에 안들어.
I don't like that face.
보기 좋은 모습이 아니야.
It ain't a pleasant face.
이런게 보기 좋은 모습이지.
Now this is a pleasant face.
조용!
Quiet!
이젠 조용해야 한다구.
I must have quiet now.
저리가, 바이올렛.
Go away, Violet.
아니, 당신에게
말만 시키지 않으면 돼요.
No, it's only
she mustn뭪 talk to you.
아주 예쁘네요.
당신과 많이 닮았어요.
She's very beautiful.
She looks very like you.
네, 다들 알아봐요.
내 동생이거든요.
Yes, everybody notices it.
She's my sister.
엄마, 아니잖아!
Ma, I ain't!
난 엄마랑 많이 닮았어요,
My face is very like
my mother's,
하지만 내 아빠들 처럼,
배가 뚱뚱하죠.
but I got a fat stomach,
just like all my fathers.
이 계집년은
대체 어디로 간거야?
Where the hell is that
god damn whore's ass?
해티!
Hattie!
아마 부두 맨 인가봐,
병이랑 이상한 물건이 많거든.
Maybe he's a voodoo man,
'cause he gots them bottles
and stuff.
아냐, 그냥 멍청이 일 뿐이야.
Nah, he's just
another dumb john.
세상에,
당장 일어나서 뭘 좀 줘.
Jesus God, woman,
get up and get me something.
머리가 깨질 것 같다구.
My head is killing me.
뭘 좀 달라구...
로드넘(아편 팅크)이나, 뭐라도.
I need something...
laudanum, something.
이런 세상에!
Jesus Christ!
엄마는 사진을 찍는 중이야,
돈도 다 냈고, 그래서 저기 있는거야.
My mama's having
her likeness made,
and it's all paid for, so there.
뭐하는거요, 참 나.
저 여자는 잘하는게 딱 한가진데.
Why, hell, man.
She's only good for one thing.
대체 뭐하러
창녀 사진을 찍으려는 거요?
Why would anybody want
to take a picture
of a piece of ass?
잠깐, 저리 좀
가달라고 부탁할께요.
Excuse me, I will have
to ask you to move away.
절대 움직이지 않고
있어야 되거든요.
She must remain
absolutely still.
어서, 허니 파이,
이제 그만둬.
Come on, Honey Pie,
now, go along, now.
아직도 술이 덜 깬 것 같은데.
You're still just
a little bit drunk.
대체 그 귀걸이는
어디서 난거야?
Where the hell
did you get those earrings?
뭐?
What?
그 에메란드 이리 내.
이런 골때리는 헛똑똑이 창녀같으니!
Give me those emeralds.
You skull-cracking,
cotton-brained whore!
어제 밤 내게 줬잖아!
You gave them to me
last night!
내가 왜 진짜 에메랄드를
창녀에게 줬겠어?
Well, why would I give
real emeralds to a whore?
나쁜자식,
God damn you,
내가 귀에 구멍을 못뚷게
할 거라고, 내기를 했잖아,
you bet me I wouldn't let you
put those holes in my ears,
뚷게 해줬으니까,
그건 내꺼야!
and I did, so those are mine!
내가 딴거라구!
I won them!
그건 내꺼란 말야!
Them's mine!
오, 이런, 귀여운 계집!
Oh, my sweet
little piece of ass!
이제 생각났어, 해티,
생각났다구.
I remember now,
Hattie, I remember.
침대로 가서 스타킹 벗어.
Go to the bed and take off
your stockings, child.
마마 모스베리,
젖꼭지 주위에 난 털이 있는데...
Mama Mosebery,
I've got this hair growing...
이젠 그걸 뽑아내는 것도
귀찮아 죽겠어.
round my nipples,
and I'm tired of plucking it.
Oh...
성 금요일에 뽑아야지!
You must pluck 'em
on Good Friday.
그 날 뽑으면,
다시는 자라지 않는다구.
Bound that same day,
and they'll never grow back.
파리에서 온 새 작업복이야?
Another new frock from Paris?
손님이 오기엔 너무 이른데
일수쟁이가 틀림 없을거야.
It's too early
for a piece of tail.
It must be the bill collector.
바이올렛, 넌 운이 좋은
꼬마 아가씨가 될거야.
Violet, you're going to be
a lucky little one.
넌 남자들이 많을 것이고,
You're going to have
so many men,
남자들을 주체하지 못할 거야.
you won't know
what to do with them.
아뇨, 지금 그녀가 바쁘면,
나중에 다시 올께요.
No, no, please,
if-if she's busy,
I'll come back later.
- 괜찮아요.
- 아뇨, 제발.
- Come on.
- No, no, please.
- 차라리 아래에서 기다릴께요.
- 어서 올라와요.
- I'd rather wait downstairs.
- Come on, come on.
현관에서 누굴 찾았는지 보라구.
자기 말로는 사진사라던데.
Look who I found
skulking in the hallway.
He say he's a photographic.
헤이, 부두맨,
방금 내 점괘를 들었어요, 볼래요?
Hey, voodoo man,
I just got my fortune told, see?
아니, 아니, 안돼요.
No, no, no, no, no.
해티에게 줄 게 있다고 하던데,
내겐 보여주지 않겠대.
He says he got something
for Hattie,
but he won't show it to me.
해티, 신사분이 찾아오셨어!
Hattie,
you got a gentleman friend!
실례했어요, 난...
아가씨들을 방해하려는게 아니고.
Oh, excuse me, I...
I didn't mean
to disturb you ladies.
미스 해티에게 줄 게 있어서요.
I... I have something
for Miss Hattie.
욕조에 있어요.
항상 욕조에 있죠.
She's in the bathtub.
She's always in the bathtub.
해티가 맘에 안내키나 본데.
난... 그냥 가보는게...
Oh, she is in-in-indisposed.
I-I... would rather...
- 뭔데요?
- 아니, 안돼.
- What's that?
- No, no, no.
이건 미스 해티를 위해
놔두는게 좋겠어.
I-I'd rather leave this off
for Miss Hattie.
내게 주지 말아요.
Don't give me that.
당신 재미있는데.
You is a sport.
헤이... 어디 카메라 좀 볼까요.
Hey... let me see your camera.
이러지 말아요.
Don't do that.
하지 말아요.
그만, 제발.
Don't do that.
Stop, please.
조심해.
Careful.
오, 정말 예쁘다.
Oh, she's so pretty.
이런, 천사같다.
Christ be, she
looks like an angel.
그렇지 않다는거 누구나 다 알아.
Everybody knows
that ain't so.
나도 이런 내 사진을 갖고 싶어.
Sure wish I had a picture
like that of myself.
그래, 고향 부모님에게도 보내주고.
Yeah, I could send
one home to my folks.
어떻게 이렇게 했어요?
How'd you do that?
좋은데, 나도 하나 있었으면.
Nice. I want one.
마술이지.
Magic.
단 1 초만 있으면 돼.
And I only need one second.
# 프리티 베이비
Well, my pretty baby
# 이리 오지 않으련
Won't you come on over here
# 사랑하는 아빠가
# 귀에 속삭이게 해다오
Let your sweet papa
whisper in your ear
# 난 젤리 롤을 너무 좋아한단다
Well, I'm wild
about the jelly roll
# 나의 달콤한 젤리 롤...
Sweet jelly roll of mine...
속임수 맞아.
Cheating is right.
넌 날 속였어.
You cheated me.
여기 내 카드가 있어...
퀸과 에이스들이야.
Well, there's my cards...
queens and aces.
네 카드 보자구.
Let's see yours.
대체 무슨 소리였지?
What the hell is it?
이거 놔!
Let me go!
네게 에이스 세 장 있었어.
I got three aces.
당신이 뭘 가졌는지 몰라.
I don't know what
you've got there.
당신 취했어.
You're drunk, man.
내 집에서 나가!
Get out of my place!
당신 집이라구?!
Your place?!
당신들 지옥으로나 꺼져!
To hell with you
and your kind!
모르겠어, 마담, 당신들은
고래 오줌 만큼 흔해 빠졌다는 거?.
And don't you know, madame,
that you are as common
as whale piss.
오!
Oh!
꺽다리,
대체 무슨 짓을 한거야?
Oh, Highpockets,
oh, what have you done to?
- 오, 이런...
- 오...
- Oh, God...
- Oh...
주정뱅이 해리는 대체 어딨는거야?
Where the hell is that bum,
Harry?
세상에, 네가 죽였어.
My God, you killed him.
그랬음 하고 바랄 뿐이야.
Well, I hope so.
해티, 쓰건 달건 받아들이라구.
Hattie, you must take
the bitters with the sweets.
론, 가서 피아노나 쳐.
Lon, go back to your piano.
바이올렛,
파이프 하나 만들어 오너라.
Violet, go make me a pipe.
이걸 감동적이라 받아들이긴 힘들구먼.
I can't take
all this emotionalizing.
해리, 이리와서
이녀석을 밖에 던져버려.
Harry, get in here
and throw him out.
그럼 안돼요.
돌아와서 날 죽일거예요.
You can't throw him out.
He'll come back and kill me.
저 빌어먹을 놈이 가게에
무슨 짓을 했는지나 보라구.
Well, look what that goddamn,
son of a bitch
did to my place.
죽게 내버려 둘 순 없어요.
Well, you just can't
leave him to die.
어떻게 하는지 구경이나 해.
Well, you just watch me.
해리, 주머니를 뒤져서
가진 걸 다 챙겨.
Harry, go through his pockets
and take everything he's got.
100 달러 밖에 없는데요.
He only has about a hundred.
그건 챙기고, 그 놈을
엠마 존슨 문앞에다 데려다 놔.
Take it all.
Drop him on Emma Johnson's
doorstep.
안돼요!
Oh, no!
그럼 이렇게 해.
가방을 싸서, 이놈과 같이 가.
Go on then.
Pack up your bags
and go with him.
사고로 그놈 머리위로 떨어진
그 망치는 치워버리라구.
And get rid of that hammer
that accidentally
dropped on him.
우린 목수 일 하지 않으니까,
망치도 필요 없어.
We don't do no carpentry work
in here,
so we don't need no hammers.
해티, 넬은
그런 뜻으로 말한게 아니야.
Hattie, you know
Nell didn't mean that.
분명 뭔가 잘못됐어, 언니 엄마가
언니를 이 집 현관에 데려 왔을 때 부터.
Something must've went wrong
when your ma was carrying you
in her pouch.
그럼, 잘못됐지.
Oh, yeah, something
went wrong.
내 엄마는 창녀였어.
My mama was a whore.
여기와 똑같은 데서 날 임신했지.
She had me in a house
just like this.
이젠 내가 창녀가 됐고, 사내들에
몸뚱이를 대주는 것 말고는 아는게 없어,
Now I'm a whore,
and I don't know anything
except a man lying on top of me,
죽을까 겁을 내면서.
임질에 걸리게 될거야.
scared to death I'm going
to get the little casino.
우리도 다 마찬가지야.
Oh, here we go again.
뉴 올린스에 병에 걸릴까봐
겁내는 창녀가 너 혼자 뿐인줄알아?
You think you're
the only whore in New Orleans
scared of getting sick?
넌 웃으면서 계속 하라구.
Oh, you just go
ahead and laugh.
넌 결국 코카인을 사려고
싸구려 웃음이나 파는 신세가 될거라구.
You're going to end up
peddling gas
for a thumbnail of cocaine.
내 트렁크를 보낼거야.
I'll send for my trunk.
누구든 자기가 원하는 대로 할
권리가 있는거야.
Everybody has a right
to do what they want.
난 존경받는 사람이 되고싶어.
I want to be a
respectable person.
노름꾼들에게?
With a gambler?
존경받는 사람들이란게 매일 밤
네 위에서 거짓말 하는 놈들이야, 해티.
It's those respectable people
who are lying on top of you
every night, Hattie.
다시 돌아올걸.
You'll be back.
아니, 안돌아올거야!
No, I won't!
여긴 단 한가지 이유 땜에 있는거야,
I'm here for one purpose
그건 철저히 내 인생을 살고
철저히 인생을 즐기려는 거라구.
and that's to live my life
to the hilt
and enjoy it the same way.
가자, 바이올렛.
Come on, Violet.
- 왜 짐을 안쌌어?
- 난 가기 싫어.
Why aren't you packed?
I don't want to go.
- 바이올렛, 난 네 엄마야.
- 아니, 엄마 아니야.
Violet, I am your mother.
No, you're not.
항상 엄마가 아니라고 했잖아.
You even say so all the time.
바이올렜, 왜이러는 거야?
Violet, why are you acting
this way?
왜, 어디 아파?
What ails you?
바이올렛?
Violet?
바이올렛, 묻고있잖아!
Violet, I'm talking to you!
이런, 머리가 깨질 것 같아.
God, I have
a splitting headache.
난 여기 있을거야.
I'm going to stay here.
얄미운 것!
I hate you.
만약... 너만 아니었으면,
난 오래 전에 여길 떳을 거야.
lf... if it weren't for you,
I would've been out of here
a long time ago.
넌 정말 이기적이야!
불공평해!
Oh, you're so selfish!
This isn't fair!
다들 자기 맘대로 하고 사는데
왜 나만 그렇게 못하는거야,
I... why does everybody else
get to do everything they want
to do around here except me
내 자신을 위해 뭔가를...
할 기회가 왔는데도 말야.
just when I get a...
a chance to do something...
for myself.
가끔 내가
태어나지 않았길 바래곤 해.
Sometimes I wish
I'd never been born.
The windin' boy,
don't deny my name...
don't deny my name
Pick it up and shake it
Like a stavin' chain
조세핀이야,
대학생들을 좋아하지.
This is Josephine
who just loves universities.
하이, 다링
- Hi, darlin'.
- Don't deny my name
Every time...
사실, 내 본명은 힐디가드야.
Actually,
my real name is Hildegarde.
친구들은 다들 힐디가드라고 불러.
My friends
all call me Hildegarde.
툴레인 대학 출신이야?
You from Tulane?
- 맞아.
- 항상 그렇더라구.
- Oh, yeah.
- I say, now, every time
Changing of that doggone moon
That old moon
정말 용감했네.
That's very brave.
Every time,
the changing of the moon
Mmm, mmm, mmm-mmm-mmm
The windin' boy,
don't deny my name.
두 아가씨가
내 운을 바꿔 놓을거야.
You two ladies are going
to change my luck.
내가 예쁘다고 생각해요?
Do you think I'm pretty?
그래, 확실히 그렇게 생각해.
Yes, I certainly do.
다른 여자들은요,
맘에 들어요?
And the other girls,
do you like them?
음, 그래.
Well, yes.
근데 왜 밤마다
여기에만 있는 거예요?
Then why do you sit here
night after night?
그 중 한명하고
윗층으로 가지 그래요?
Why don't you go upstairs
with any of them?
그 이유를 난 알지만,
넌 알아내야겠구나.
That is for me to know
and for you to find out.
- 아저씨 나이 많죠?
- 그래 많아..
You're very old, aren't you?
Yes, very old.
- 아주, 아주 많아요?
- 그래, 아주 아주 많아.
Very, very old?
Yes, very, very old.
- 얼마 못살 것 같아요?
- 아니, 그렇진 않아.
Do you think
you'll be dead soon?
No, I don't think so.
- 왜 그렇지 않다 생각하는데요?
- 음, 아직은 죽을 것 같지 않은데.
Well, why don't you think so?
Well, I don't feel
like being dead yet.
너무 젊거든.
I'm too young.
나이가 많다고 해놓구선,
어떻게 너무 젊다는거예요?
You said you're old, so
how can you be too young?
한잔 해야겠어.
Got to wet my whistle.
- 난 아저씨가 오래 못살 것 같아요.
- 왜?
Well, I think
you'll be dead soon.
Oh, why?
마담 넬이 그랬거든요.
아저씨는 죽는게 더 낫대요.
'Cause Madame Nell said so.
She said you'd be
better off dead.
- 죽는게 더 낫다고?
- 음-흠.
Oh, better off dead?
Uh-huh.
아저씨는 뭔가 잘못됐대요.
동성애 자거나, 뭐 그렇대요.
Madame says there's
something wrong with you.
That you're some kind of
cream puff, or something.
아저씨가 불쌍하대요,
인생의 재미를 다 잃어버려서.
She thinks that you're pathetic,
missing all the fun in life.
마담 넬은 자기가 아는 것 보다
더 많이 안다고 착각을 하나보다.
Perhaps Madame Nell is imagining
she knows more than she does.
- 그녀가 재있게 사는 것 같니?
- 누구보다도 행복하게 살고있어요.
You think she's having fun?
She's as happy as anybody.
성병에 걸리게 될까봐 겁나요?
Are you afraid
you'll get little casino?
임질 말예요?
The clap?
아니야.
Oh. No.
그런데 왜요?
Well, why then?
뭐 하나 물어볼까?
Do I ask you questions?
꼬마에게 날 설명할 필요 없어.
I don't have to explain
myself to a child.
난 꼬마가 아니예요.
I'm not a child.
이런, 그건 네생각이지.
Excuse me,
that is your opinion.
귀찮게하지마.
Leave me alone.
아저씬 날 미워해요.
You hate me.
난 사랑하거나 미워할 시간 없어.
I have no time
for hate or love.
이런 꼬마야,
넌 아주 팔팔하구나.
Dear child,
you're so full of life.
내 기력을
뺏어갈 필요 없잖니, 안그래?
You don't have to take mine,
do you?
아-하.
이 아가씨는 누구야?
Ah-hah.
Well, what have we here?
이젠 꼬마 아가씨도 팝니까, 마담 넬?
백인 노예 말예요, 어?
Are you selling little girls
now, Madame Nell?
White slavery, huh?
- 헤이, 키스 할 줄 알아?
- 당연하죠, 그걸 누가 몰라요.
Hey, do you know how to kiss?
Of course I do.
Everybody does.
너 그사람 조심해, 바이올렛.
Well, you watch out for him,
Violet.
가시덤불 같은 마음을 가졌는데...
He's got a heart
like an artichoke...
모든 여자들을 위한 잎이 나있고
끝마다 가시가 달려있다구.
a leaf for every girl
and a prick on the end
of each one of them.
말해봐, 어디서 이렇게 진주처럼
예쁜 치아와 멋진 갈색 머리칼을 났지?
Now tell me where'd you get
those pretty pearly teeth
and that beautiful brown hair?
엄마가 매일 뜨게 바늘로
이빨을 깨끗이 해주고,
My mama puts my teeth in
every morning with a crocheter,
갈색 머리는 내가 골랐어요,
먼지가 눈에 안뜨이거든요.
and I chose brown hair
'cause it don't show the dirt.
Mmm.
안, 안돼.
No. No, no.
안된다구,
그건 내 스타일이 아니예요.
No, no, that's-that's-that's
not my style, you know.
그냥 장난한 거였어요.
I was just kidding around.
맛사지 해주면 뭐 줄래요?
What will you give me
for a message?
내가 잘 아는 것을 알려줄께.
I'll give you
the back of my hand
is what I'll give you.
아래에 나 찾아온 사람 없니?
Is there someone
down there for me?
음-흠.
멍청이 영감이 또 왔어요, 으.
Mm-hmm.
It's that horrible
old coot again. Ugh.
그 염감에게 버릇없이 굴지마.
Do not be so snotty
about him.
그런 늙고 어리석은 생각으로 날
좋아해야, 여길 빠져나갈수 있다구.
That old fool's idea
that he likes me,
is my ticket
out of this place.
게다가,
부자라구.
And besides,
he is rich.
전화번호부를 보고 알았어,
세인트 찰스에 살고있다구.
I know because I looked him up
in the phone book,
and he lives on St. Charles.
그 영감은 이 세상에서
원하는건 뭐든 가질 수 있어...
And he could have whatever
he wants in the world...
그리고 날 원한다구...
and he wants me...
자기에게 아무 관심도 없는 사람을.
...who doesn't give a damn
for him.
나를... 자기에게
아무 관심도 없는 사람을.
Me... who doesn't give a damn
for him.
여긴 내 딸 바이올렛이예요.
This is my little girl,
Violet.
지금 몇살이지, 바이올렛?
And how old are you, Violet?
몰라요.
I don't know.
- 맘에 들어요?
- 아주 예쁜데.
Do you like her?
She is very pretty.
넬 말대로, 친구들만 가능해요.
아직 숫처녀거든요.
Like Nell says,
she's only for friends,
so she's still a virgin.
음, 다 됐어.
긴장 풀라구.
Well, I have it now.
You may relax.
죽을 것 같은 느낌이야.
I feel like I'm going to croak.
바이올렛, 마실 것 좀 가져와.
Violet, honey,
go get us a drink.
전쟁 전에는,
여름에는 문을 닫았었는데,
Before the war,
we used to close down
in the summertime,
해군 기지가 들어온 이후로는
1 년 내내 바빠요.
but since the naval base came,
we're busy all year round now.
- 한잔 줄까요?
- 아니, 됐어.
Can I buy you a drink?
No, thank you.
한장 더 찍고 싶은데
괜찮겠어?
Perhaps we could
make another one now.
Would you like to?
네, 안될 것 있나요?
Yeah, why not?
난 가슴이 아주 멋져요
. 다른 어떤 애들 가슴보다 멋지죠.
My breasts are very nice.
They're nicer
than any of the other girls'.
가슴을 좀 내보여야
될 것 같지 않아요?
Do you think maybe I should just
show 'em a little bit?
그래, 그럼 더 좋을 것 같네.
어디 볼까.
Yes, that would be better.
Let me... let me see.
어때요?
Well?
피부가 아주 좋군.
You have fine skin.
화이트 파우더 있어?
Do you have any white powder?
그럼요... 바로 거기요.
Sure, surely... right over there.
그걸 어깨부분에 발라.
그래, 가슴에도 바르고.
Put it on your shoulders here.
Yes, and-and on your breast.
프래니 벗은 모습을
찍은 사진이 맘에들어요.
I love the one you made
of Fanny naked.
걔는 뚱뚱해요.
She sure is fat.
프래니는 아름다워...
Fanny's beautiful...
하지만 빛이 마음에 안들었어.
but I wasn't pleased
with the light.
이제 준비 다 됐지?
So, you're all
ready for me now?
만족스러워?
Are you content?
꼬마야, 넌 이제
그만 가야겠다.
Child, I'm afraid
you'll have to go now.
나요?
Me?
뒤로 젖혀서...
Lie back against...
머리를 여기에 대.
put you head here.
그렇지, 어...
Yes, uh...
그 쪽으로 돌아 누워 보겠어?
Can you lay on-on your side?
그렇지.
That's it.
그리고 손을 머리 뒤로 하라구.
And put-put your hand
behind your head.
그거야.
That's it.
완벽해.
움직이지마.
That's perfect.
Don't move.
그대로 있으라구.
Don't move at all.
정말 아름다워.
You look very beautiful.
아름다움 자체야.
Just beautiful.
이순간이 정말 행복해.
I'm very happy just now.
몇 초만 있으면,
완벽하게 찍힐거야.
Just a few seconds, and it will
all be there perfectly.
자, 움직이지 마.
Now, don't move.
아주 좋은 사진이 될거야.
That one should be very nice.
자, 그대로 있어.
Now, don't move.
다시는 절대 그러지 마!
Never, never do that!
네가 무슨 짓을
할 뻔 했는지나 알아!
You have no idea
what you might have done!
사진을 보려고 그런 것 뿐이야!
아무 짓도 안했다구요!
I only wanted to see
the picture.
I didn't do anything!
바이올렛...
Violet...
기다려야만 해.
you have to wait.
이건 네거티브일 뿐이야.
This is only a negative.
현상을 해야되고,
또 인화를 해야...
It has to be developed,
and printed, and...
그래야만...
and then...
엄마를 사랑해.
You love her.
내 느낌엔 상관 마.
Don't tell me how I feel.
자, 바이올렛...
Now, Violet...
정말 미안해...
I'm very sorry...
하지만 네가 하루 종일
한 일을 망칠 뻔 했어,
but you might've ruined
a whole day's work for me,
너도 미안해 해야해.
so you should be sorry, too.
내 느낌에 상관마요.
Don't tell me how I feel.
난 아저씨를 알아요.
I know about you.
엄마를 사랑하는거예요.
You love her.
내버려둬요.
쑈하는 거니까.
Leave her be.
She's just showing off.
가요, 내려가서 뭐 좀 먹자구요.
Come on,
let's go down and eat.
난 저게 더 좋아.
I like that one better.
불쌍한 여자들에게
바가지를 씌우려고하네.
Trying to rob
a poor working girl.
25 쎈트 이상은 안돼.
I'll give you 25 cents
and no more.
- 말야, 그 세개 1달러 씩에 줄께.
- 1 달러?
I am... three each.
- Sell it to you for a dollar.
- A dollar?
이 블라우스 카날 스트리트에서
50 쎈트에 팔던데.
I saw the same blouse
on Canal Street for 50 cents.
아!
Ah.
물론, 어... 난 여자들이
위 아래가 좀 더 큰 게 좋던데.
Course, uh... I likes my women
with a little more
on the top and bottom.
뻔뻔하게 굴지마요, 부두 워먼을
데려가 피아노에 그리스를 바르기 전에.
Stop being so cheeky with me,
or I'll get my voodoo woman
to put gris gris
all over your piano.
바이올렛, 이리 좀 와봐,
가까이서 드레스 좀 보게.
Violet, come on down here,
and let me see
the front of that dress.
바이올렛,
그건 드레스라고 할수도 없어.
Oh, Violet,
that ain't much of a dress.
머리를 올리러 갈 때는,
붉은 새틴이 최고라구.
When you're going to bust
your cherry,
you best wear red satin.
저러니 멍청한 검둥이래지...
그렇게 밖에 생각을 못하니까.
That's why
you're a dumb nigger...
'cause you think like that.
얜 처녀라구.
시시한 창녀처럼 입었음 좋겠어?
She's a virgin.
Do you want her to be dressed
like a Picayune whore?
이런, 프리다,
너 강낭콩 처럼 시퍼렇다.
My God, Frieda,
you're as green as a goose turd.
- 이게 뭐야?
- 열어봐.
What's this?
Open it and see.
검은 고양이 꼬리의
9 번째 뼈야...
It's the ninth bone
from the tail
of a black cat...
오늘 네게 행운을 가져다 줄거야.
guaranteed to bring you luck
tonight.
레드 탑!
Red Top!
명심해, 남자는 처녀를 산거니까,
처녀인 것 처럼 행동해야해.
Do not forget
that this guy's
buying a virgin,
so she's got to act it right.
그 남자에게 넌 아무 것도
모른다는 인상을 줘야해.
You've got to give him
the idea
that you don't know nothing.
강간을 당하는 것처럼.
Should be like a rape.
네가 어떻게 알아.
You don't know.
다른걸 원하는 사람일지도 몰라...
잠자리를 원하는 듯이 하길 바라는.
Could be a different kind
of guy...
someone that wants you to act
like she wants it.
중요한 것은 남자가 시작 할 때
흐느껴 우는거야,
The main thing is
to whimper and cry
at first when he starts,
하지만 그 다음엔
느낌이 좋은 듯 행동하는 거지.
but then you've got to
act like it feels good.
나도 다 알아.
가만 좀 두라구.
I know what to do.
Leave me alone.
다 아는 듯이 하지 말란 말이야.
그랬다간 팁도 못받을테니까.
Well, don't act
like you know it all.
You won't even get a tip
that way.
바이올렛, 남자... 거시기를
실수로 만진 것 처럼 건드려야 해.
Violet, you should
touch him... there...
you know... like it's accidental.
알아... 나도 다 안다구.
I know... I know all that.
바이올렛, 넌 예쁘니까,
Violet, you is
a beautiful girl.
네게 필요한 것은 예쁜 드레스와
상황을 정교하게 할 다이아몬드만 있음 돼.
Now, all you need
is that handsome dress
and plenty diamonds
to elaborate the condition.
음식이 아주 좋았어.
That was good.
맛있게 드셨다니 좋네요.
You better enjoy it.
우리집에서 마지막으로 먹은
훌륭한 저녁이니까요.
It's the last fine dinner
you'll get on me.
- 오, 이런, 안돼.
- 안돼, 안돼.
- Oh, hell, no.
- No, no, no.
안그래요, 의원님?
Isn't that so, Senator?
해군에서 이 구역을
폐쇄할 계획이라던데.
The Navy's going to close
the district down.
내가 미 해군과 싸울 수야 없지.
Well, I can't fight
the United States Navy.
이미 애를 써 봤지만,
어쩔 수 없었어.
We tried that already,
and we lost.
앉아, 바이올렛, 그래야 쉬워.
Sit down, Violet, it's easier.
파우더 바르는 것 좀 도와줄까?
Honey, you want me to help you
put your powder on, or anything?
- 아니, 내가 할 수 있어.
- 알았어.
No, I can do it myself.
All right.
이런, 재가 태어난게 기억에 생생한데
이제 머리를 올리려 하고 있다니.
God, I could remember
when she was born,
and now she's busting
her cherry.
세상에, 프래니, 재가 태어날 때
넌 겨우 여섯 살이었어.
Jesus, Fanny, you were
only six years old
when she was born.
이런, 당신 멋지지않아요?
My, my, aren't you handsome?
왜 전에 여기 안왔었죠?
Why haven't
you been here before?
당신은 딱 제 스타일의 남자예요.
You're just my kind of man.
오, 이것 봐요.
Oh, look at that.
그걸 어디다 숨겨두고 있었죠?
Where you been hiding
that thing?
그걸 얼마동안이나
가지고 있었죠, 쉐리?
How long has it been
for you, Cherie?
여기 누워요.
Lie down right here.
어서 내게 줘요, 베이비.
Give it to me, baby.
진정한 처녀.
A virgin, bona fide.
몇살이지?
How old is she?
날 감옥에 집어넣으려구요?
나이라면 먹을만큼 먹었어요.
Do you want to put me in jail?
She's just old enough.
뉴 올린스 최고의
우아한 자태예요,
The finest delicacy
New Orleans has to offer,
저 아이가 바라는 것은, 여러분 중
한 분이 첫 남자가 되어주는 거예요.
and it's her wish
that one of you gentlemen
be the first.
응접실로 따라 오시면,
기회를 얻을 수 있을 거예요.
If you'll all join me
in the parlor,
you'll get your opportunity.
어서, 빨리해.
Come on, quick.
거기 리본 좀 줘.
Give me the ribbon, child.
어서.
Come on.
얼마를 부를까요, 여러분?
What am I bid, gentlemen?
사기 전에 살펴보는게
법도 아니던가요?
Don't we get a look
before we buy?
켄트, 잘 살펴봐요.
Kent, you can look
all you want.
물건을 깨트리지만 말고.
Just don't break
the merchandise.
처녀란걸 어떻게 알죠?
Hey, how do we know
she is a virgin?
내가 당신에게 거짓말 한 적 있소?
만족할 거라 보장하죠.
Have I ever lied
to you before?
Satisfaction guaranteed.
자, 여러분,
기다리게 하지 말아요.
Well, gentlemen,
I'm getting impatient.
100 달러 내겠소.
I'll bid a hundred dollars.
예~!
Yeah!
120 달러.
I'm bidding $120.
150 달러.
$150.
오, 그럼.
Oh, well, now.
50 달러!
$50!
잘했어요, 의원님, 잘했어요.
Beautiful, Senator,
just beautiful.
명심하세요, 여러분,
어린아이의 입술처럼 싱싱하다는 것을.
Remember, gentlemen,
she's as fresh
as a baby's lips.
160 달러.
$160.
165 달러.
$165.
175 달러.
$175.
180 달러.
$180.
난 감당 못하겠는데.
Getting out of my reach.
200 달러.
$200.
봐요, 보라구요... 210.
Gentlemen, gentlemen... $210.
225로 올리죠.
I'll top that with $225.
230 내겠소.
Well, I'll bid $230.
좋아, 240 달러.
All right, $240.
250.
$250.
275 달러요, 마담.
$275, madame.
280.
$280.
300.
$300.
스표도 받을거요?
Will you take a check?
수표를 가지고 뭐하라구?
What would I do with a check?
현금.
Cash.
현금 있어요. 400 달러.
I got cash. $400.
세상에, 누구야,
록펠러?
Jesus Christ, who is he,
Rockefeller?
헤이, 이건 우리 형편을
넘어선 것이오.
Hey, this is kind of
out of our league.
우린 그런 돈 없어요.
We don't have
that kind of money.
봐요, 이건 우릴 위한 밤이오.
Look, this is our night.
당신은 초대받지 않았잖소.
You weren't invited here.
당신이 뭔데 이래?
Who do you think you are?
헤이, 지금 뭐하는 거예요!
Hey, watch what you're doing!
조심해, 친구들.
Watch out, fellas.
400 달러,
현금으로 내신 분께 낙찰됐어요.
Sold to the man
with 400 cash.
시키는 대로 말 잘들어.
Do not give him any argument.
위스키 좀 줄까?
You want some whiskey?
이런, 다 마시라는 말이 아니었는데.
Well, Jesus, I didn't mean
the whole damn thing.
당신이어서 기뻐요.
I'm glad it's you.
왜 나여서 기쁘다는거지?
Why are you glad it's me?
음... 잘생기셨고, 또...
가슴이 좋으니까요.
Well... you look nice, and...
you have a nice chest.
내 안에있는 증기가
드레스로 빠져나가는게 느껴져요.
I can feel the steam inside me
right through my dress.
젊은 아가씨를 맛보게 둡시다.
Let him have his young peach.
난 원숙한 아가씨가 좋아, 안그래?
I like my fruit ripe, eh?
저걸 보니 구역질이 나려고 하는군.
Gives me queasy innards
to see a thing like that.
잠금 고리 없어?
Isn't there a lock?
마담 넬은
문을 못잠그게 해요.
Madame Nell don't allow
no locks.
빌어먹을, 400 달러나 냈는데,
문에 잠금고리는 있어야지.
God damn, for $400,
I'd like to have
that door locked.
부드럽게 해 주셨음 좋겠어요,
제 첫남자로서요.
I hope you're going to be
real gentle on me,
being my first time.
위스키 드려요?
Want a whiskey?
제발요...
Please...
잠시 둘러보러 갈거예요?
You want to go for
a little roll in the kip?
정말로 잠시 어찌되었나
보러 안갈거예요?
Are you sure
you don't want to go
for a little roll in the kip?
여긴 냄새가 않좋은데.
It smells bad in here.
- 기분이 안좋으세요?
- 기분 좋아.
You're feeling badly?
Oh, I feel fine.
기분도 좋고,
행복하다구.
I feel all right.
I'm happy.
기분좋아,
I feel fine,
내가 맘만 먹으면 여기 있는
모든 남자들 부탁을 들어줄 수도 있어.
and I could probably
accommodate personally
every man of the house
if I decided to.
바이올렛?
Violet?
이런.
Jesus.
마담?!
Madame?!
바이올렛?
Violet?
의사를 불러와!
Get a doctor!
죽었나봐!
She's been murdered!
바이롤렛?
오, 내 딸아!
Violet? Oh, my baby!
바이올렛?
Violet?
애야?
Baby?
대체 모두 다
디 있었던거야?
Well, I'd like to know
where the hell y'all been?
내가 여기
영원히 누워있는 데.
I been lying here forever.
오...
Oh...
내 걱정은 하나도 안하고.
You don't care about me at all.
바이올렛,
간떨어질 뻔 했잖아.
Oh, Violet, that
really wasn't funny.
그런줄 나도 알아.
내가 지금 웃는 것 같아?
I know it's not funny.
Am I laughing?
너도 이제
제대로 경험한거야, 어?
So, you had a live one, huh?
보라구, 그게 중요한거야.
Come on,
that's what it's all about.
이제 네가 우리 몸이 안좋을 땐
늦잠을 자도 가만 두겠구나.
Maybe now you'll let us sleep
in the morning
when we feel bad.
전쟁에, 아버지는 죽었고,
엄마는 일을 해야만 했죠.
The war, father got killed,
mother forced to go to work.
이 아이는 처녀예요.
You know, she's a virgin.
처녀인건 별로 관심 없지만,
성병에 대한 얘기를 들었어요.
Oh, I ain't too particular
about the virgin part,
but I hear tell
there's disease.
여긴 병있는 아가씨는 없어요.
I got no sick girls here,
monsieur.
- 누가 우리 집을 알려줬죠, 친구?
- 네.
Who told you about my place,
a friend?
Yes'm.
친구분 말을 못믿으신다면...
Well, if you can't trust
a friend...
자, 어때요?
Now, how about it?
순결하죠,
방금 쌓인 눈처럼.
Pure
as the driven snow.
와인 좀 주실래요?
Can I have a little bit of wine?
고마워요.
날 망쳐놓으시네요.
Thank you.
You spoil me.
오, 이런.
심장이 멎는줄 알았어요.
Oh, my gosh.
That took my breath away.
비가 오는 날에 할 건 2 가지 뿐인데,
카드 놀이를 하고 싶진 않아.
There are only two things
to do on rainy days,
and I don't like
to play cards.
건배해요.
I propose a toast.
오.
Oh.
전쟁이 빨리 끝난걸 환영하며.
To a quick end of the war.
예~!
Yeah.
종전을 환영하며.
To the end of the war.
새예요.
잡아요.
A bird.
Catch it.
- 잡아!
- 오!
- Get it!
- Oh!
Oh, wow.
불실한 징조야.
죽음을 의미한다구.
It's bad luck.
It means death.
창문을 열어.
날아갈거야.
Open the damn windows.
It'll fly out.
안돼, 들어온 곳으로
나가야만 해요.
No. It has to go out
the same way it came in.
오, 차라리 새를 잡아야겠어.
Oh, I better get
that little bird.
이리 내려와!
내려와... 야...
Come down here!
Come down... you...
- 예쁘지?
-정말 조그많다.
Ain't it pretty?
It's so tiny.
Love
Oh, love
Oh, careless love
어서, 부끄러워 말고.
응?
Come on, honey.
Don't be shy.
Please?
Won't you see
what careless love will do?
어서, 사람들에게 얘기 해.
Now. Tell 'em for me now,
please.
쉬~! 쉬!
Shh! Shh! Shh!
어...
Well, uh...
해티에게 청혼을 했어요,
해티도 동의했고, 우린 결혼할거예요.
I've asked Hattie to be my wife,
and she has personally agreed,
so we're going to be married.
멋진데요.
Oh, that's great.
우리도 결혼을 할거예요.
We're going to have a wedding.
언제? 다들 준비되어있거든요.
When? 'Cause we are ready.
사실, 이사람
고향에가서 결혼하기로 했어.
Well, actually,
we're-we're going to get married
in his hometown.
맞아요, 그러니까...
세인트루이스에 작은 집이 있어요...
Yeah, you see, I, um...
I got me this little house
in St. Louis, Missouri,
so, uh...
거기서 결혼을 할 예정이죠.
I kind of thought
we'd be married there.
해티, 결국 한사람에게
코가 꿰었구나?
Well, Hattie,
you finally nailed one, huh?
내 말에 대답 안할거니,
바이올렛?
Aren't you going to answer me,
Violet?
이럴 수 밖에 없었어. 그이가 오늘
올 때 까지 진심이었는지도 몰랐고.
I had to do it this way.
I wasn't even sure
he really meant it
until he come today.
근데 반지랑,
모든걸 가져왔더라.
But he's got the ring
and everything.
우리에겐 정말 중요한 일이 될거야.
It's going to be
really big things for us.
넌 내 동생이라고 말했고,
그이는 그런줄로 알고있어.
I told him that
you was my sister.
He don't know any different.
적절한 때가 되면
그이에게 얘기 할거야.
As soon as the
right time comes,
I'm going to tell him.
다행이도 리틀 윌은
문제삼지 않았어.
It's lucky
he doesn't even mind
about Little Will.
먹을래요?
Want some?
해티, 기차가 30 분 후에 떠나.
Hattie, our-our train leaves
in a half an hour.
좋아, 이제 가야겠어.
All right, honey.
I'm coming.
잘가.
Auf Wiedersehen.
말야, 편지할께.
그건 약속할수있어.
Honey, I'll send for you.
I promise you that.
오.
내 모습 괜찮니?
Oh.
Do I look all right?
한장.
One card.
한장 줘, 알.
One card, Al.
색다른 걸 하고싶지 않아?
오늘 우리 휴가라구.
Don't you fellows want
to do something?
It's our day off.
지금 뭔가 하고 있잖아.
Well, we are doing something.
말도안돼,
남자들이 이 많은 창녀들과
I tell you,
you put men in a room
with a bunch of whores,
한방에 있으면서,
고작 포커나 하다니.
and all they want to do
is play poker.
이해가 인되는 아저씨들이네.
Never understand men.
그래, 정말이야.
Yeah, really.
아직 파파가 있는걸.
Well, we still have Papa.
모두 나랑 쇼 보러갈까?
Shall I take you all
to the burlesque?
아니면 영화를 보러 가든지.
Or we could go
to the picture show.
알았다.
사딘 놀이 하자.
I know.
Let's play Sardines.
- 그래.
- 좋아.
- Yeah.
그럼...
파파도 하면 되겠다.
And Papa... Papa can be it.
사딘 놀이 할 줄 모르는데,
들어본 적도 없어.
I don't know this game,
Sardines.
I never heard of it.
- 배울거에요.
- 알게 된다구요.
- You'll learn.
- You'll find out.
우리가 만들었는데,
정말 재밌다구요.
We made it up.
It's really a lot of fun.
어떻게 하는 것인데?
Well, how do you play?
One, two,
three, four,
five,
six, seven,
eight, nine,
ten!
- 침대 아래를 봐.
- 알았어.
Look under the bed.
Okay.
아그네스 방엔 없어.
He's not in Agnes' room.
파파!
Papa!
제길.
Goddamn it.
찾았어?
Did you find him?
파파?
Papa?
여기 있는거 알아.
I know you're in here.
남쪽으로 날아가야 될거야,
맞지?
We'll just have
to fly south. See?
거시 언니 방을 안봤네.
I didn't look
in Gussie's room.
제길!
Damn it!
너무 쉽네요
. 숨소리가 다 들려요.
You're easy.
I heard you breathing.
오!
Oh!
내 키스 좋았어요?
Did you like that?
Come on.
헤이.
Hey.
정말 좋지 않았어.
종용히 있게 하기가 어려웠다구.
He's been real bad.
It's been hard
to keep him quiet.
들어와, 어서.
Get in, get in.
사딘. 어-허.
Sardine. Uh-uh.
사딘 잡았다!
Caught your sardine!
그 아래에 뭐야?
What's under there?
근데 슈크림은 없는데!
Bet they're ain't
no cream puffs!
좋아.
All right.
우!
Whoo!
속임수야.
게임에 지는 걸 싫어하거든.
It's just a trick.
She hates to be losing a game.
이런, 정말 떨어졌나봐.
God, there sure was a fall.
우습네,
내가 뭘 부수다니.
Funny, I think
I broke something.
네가 부순거 맞아.
You broke something,
all right.
당신을 한 번 사랑했고,
I love you once,
두 번 사랑했고,
콩과 쌀알 숫자 보다 더 사랑해요.
I love you twice.
I love you
more than beans and rice.
그 사람이 뭐래?
말해봐.
What did he say?
Come on.
Mademoiselle
from Armenti?es
Parlez-vous
Mademoiselle
from Armentieres
Parlez-vous
The officers
get all the take
And all I get is a bellyache
Inky-dinky parlez-vous.
교수님에게 뭘 좀
해드리는게 어때요?
How about a little something
for the professor?
쟤는 앞으로 어떻게 되는거죠?
What will become of her now?
대체 왜그러는거야?
What's going on with you?
당신이 걱정할 일이 아니야.
You don't have
to worry about her.
재는 돈을 잘 벌고 있다구.
She's made a lot of money.
자기가 원하는 대로 할 수 있어.
She can do as she likes.
겨우 12 살에,
완전히 혼자라구요!
She's-she's only 12.
She's completely alone.
- 벨라크, 저 아이를 사랑하는군.
- 터무니 없는 소리.
Bellocq,
you're in love with her.
Don't be absurd.
이런 걸 1 백번도 더봤어.
I've seen it a hundred times.
난 늙었고.
I am old.
인생은 너무도 길지.
And life is so long.
Oh, yeah, I love you,
little woman
She's my baby
My joy
and little woman
I love her...
She's crazy little...
웅얼거리지 좀 마.
Stop that goo-gooing.
고마워, 고맙다구, 난...
Thank you, thank you. I...
천만에.
그게 필요한줄 알았어.
You're quite welcome.
I knew you needed it.
5.
내가 뭘 던졌지?
Five.
What did I roll?
- 8.
- Eight.
- 고마워.
- 천만에.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
8 나왔다.
I got an eight.
그래, 8 이네.
Yeah, you got an eight.
내가 이겻어.
I'm winning.
잘했어.
Very good.
5.
Five.
9.
Nine.
Go ahead.
나도 사진을 찍을 준비가
다 된 것 같아서 여기 서있는거에요.
I'm standing here
thinking I'm ready
to get my picture took.
- 바이올렛, 제발 비켜줘.
- 비켜, 바이올렛.
Violet, please go away.
Go away, Violet.
5 나왔다.
내가 이겼어.
I got a five.
I won.
멍청한 늙다리!
You're stupid and old.
레드 탑...
Red Top...
네가 커서 수염을 기르게 되면,
...when you grow up, and you
have a beard and a mustache,
네가 멋있다고 생각하게 될거야.
I'm going to think
you're very handsome.
그럼 네 것이
단단하고 커지게 사랑해 줄거야.
And I'm going to love you up
hard and long.
특별히 내가 그렇다는건,
Well, especially me,
내게 네 기둥서방이라서 일걸.
'cause I am the lover boy.
장담하는데, 니들 모두
아무 짓도 못해봤을걸.
I bet neither of you
never done nothing.
뭐?
Huh?
어제도 여자하고 잤는걸.
I had me a piece of tail
yesterday.
이 동네 여자들은
모두 내게 공짜로 해준다구.
All the girls in the district
give me free lovin'.
맞아.
Yeah.
나니, 넌 해본 적 없어,
해봤어?
Nonny, you never did it,
did you?
그럼, 해봤지.
그것도 여러번.
Of course I have.
Lots of times.
그럼, 느낌이 어땠는지 말해봐.
Then tell me what
it feels like.
아주 좋았지.
세상에, 뭐가 더있겠어?
Well, it feels good.
For God sakes,
what else?
어떤 느낌인지 정확히 말해봐.
Tell me exactly how it feels.
어떤 느낌인지 알아,
I knows how it feels,
근데 뭐라고 해야 할 지
몰라서 그렇지.
but-but I just don't know
how to describe it.
등이 간질거리는 듯한 이상한 느낌이,
발가락이 간질거리는 걸로 시작되지.
It's like you get this tingling
feeling along on your back,
and this funny feeling starts
creeping up your toes.
해봐, 나니.
Do it, Nonny.
뭐?
얘가 미쳤나봐.
What?
You must be crazy.
당장 내게 해봐.
할 수 있다는걸 보여줘.
Do it to me right now.
Prove you can.
난 크다구,
꼬맹이, 어?
I'm big, you're little, huh?
저리가.
Get off me.
널 애인으로 만들거야, 나니.
I'm going to make you
my lover man, Nonny.
네 것이 단단하고 커지게
사랑해 줄거야.
I'm going to love you up
real hard and long.
이거 놔!
이거 놓으라구!
Let me up!
무슨 일인지 말해볼래?
What you gonna say, boy?
아니예요.
Nothing.
아무 말도 안할거예요.
He ain't gonna say nothing.
바이올렛...
너 정말 뻔뻔하구나,
Violet, baby...
you is very bold,
그렇게 자란 거야,
넌 진짜 세상이 어떤지 아무 것도 몰라.
and the way you been raised,
you don't know nothing
about real world.
백인과 흑인은, 같이 잘 수 없어.
적어도 그 문제는 그래.
White and colored...
they can't be together,
as far as that's concerned.
내 맘대로 할 수 있어.
모두들 모든 사람과 그러는걸.
I can do what I want.
Everybody does that
with everybody.
흑인하고도?
흑인이 그걸 하러 윗층에 가는거 봤어?
And colored?
Did you see colored men upstairs
for that?
아니, 못봤을 거야, 바이올렛.
No, you don't, Violet.
난 교회에 나가고,
목사 주례로 결혼했어,
I'm a church-going woman
that was married by a preacher,
내가 하는 말은
나니를 가만 두라는 거야.
and what I can say
is you've gots to leave
my Nonny alone.
너무 지나쳤어, 바이올렛.
You pushing far, Violet.
맞아, 그랬어.
해리!
She certainly is.
Harry!
오! 내려줘!
Oh! Let me... go!
내려 줘!
Let me go!
안돼! 난...
No! I want...
내려 달라구!
Oh, let me go!
안돼!
No!
아우!
Ow!
얘를 때리면 안되죠.
사람을 때리는 걸 배울 뿐이예요.
You can't beat a child.
It only teaches her
to beat others.
난 내일을 할테니,
당신 일에나 신경써, 파파.
I'll run my business,
and you tend to yours, Papa.
하나도 안아파.
It didn't hurt.
황소 고집에,
철판 엉덩이네.
Hard headed and hard-assed.
- 헤이, 파파, 저녁 안먹고 갈래요?
- 아니, 고마워.
Hey, Papa, you sure
you won't stay for dinner?
No, no, thank you.
여길 어떻게 알고 왔지?
And how did you find me?
전화번호부에서 봤어요.
누구라도 그건 생각한다구요.
I looked you up
in a telephone book.
Anybody can think of that.
난 전화 없어, 바이올렛.
I don't have a telephone,
Violet.
아저씨를 따라 왔었어요...
여러 번.
Well, I followed you here...
lots of times.
저녁은 먹었니?
Have you had your supper?
이게 다 뭐예요?
What's all this?
일하고 있었어.
I've been working.
그러니까, 이게 일이군요...
사진 찍는것?
You mean, this is your work...
photographing?
그래, 이걸로 먹고산다구.
Yes. This is how
I earn my living.
세상에, 아주 쉽네요.
God, that's so easy.
집안일 하는 거 보다 쉽겠어요.
Well, easier
than working in a house.
도망치기로 작정했나보네.
You've decided to run away.
어디서 자요?
Where do you sleep?
윗층에서.
Upstairs.
봐야겠어요.
I want to see it.
왜 잠궈뒀어요?
Why do you lock it?
글쎄... 버릇이야.
I don't know... habit.
가끔 애들이 집안으로 들어와.
Sometimes children
break into my house.
왜요?
Why?
아마 나랑 카메라가 신기한가봐.
I imagine they're curious
about me and my camera.
이웃과 사이가 안좋아.
The neighborhood has turned bad.
왜요?
Why?
왜, 왜, 왜.
나도 이유는 몰라.
Why, why, why.
I don't know why.
창녀집 때문이겠지.
'Cause of the whorehouses.
왜 전기가 없는거예요?
How come you ain't
got no electricity?
이 방이 맘에 들어요.
Well, I like this room.
우카, 두카...
Ooka, dooka...
그걸 하고 놀았나 보구나?
Well, you certainly did it,
didn't you?
바이올렛?
Violet?
여기 있어도 돼요?
Can I stay here?
그래, 되지, 네가 원하면.
Yes, you may, if you want to.
그래요! 나랑
같이 자고 돌봐줄 거예요?
I do! Will you sleep with me
and take care of me?
아니.
No.
왜요?
And why not?
그건...
Because...
- 왜 그런지 잘 모르겠는데.
- 어-허, 날 무서워하는군요.
'cause I'm not
sure why, exactly.
Uh-huh. You're afraid of me.
- 아마도.
- 내 애인이 되어주세요,
- Perhaps.
- I want you
to be my lover,
내게 스타킹이랑 옷도 사주고...
and buy me stockings,
and clothes, and...
넌 그게
무슨 말인지도 몰라, 바이올렛.
You don't know what
you're saying, Violet.
아저씨에겐 돈 안받을께요,
I won't even charge you
anything at all,
내 집으로 찾아 올수도 있고
내 팬시 맨(가둥서방)이 돼줘요.
and you can visit me
at my house
and be my fancy man.
그 집에서 도망친 줄 알았는데.
I thought you were running away
from the house.
맞아요. 자기들이 뭔데
날 그렇게 때려요..., 난 안돼요.
Oh, yes.
They can't beat me like that...
well, not me.
- 전적으로 동감이야.
- 그래요?
I agree absolutely.
You do?
안그랬다면 널 벌써 때려줬을 걸,
침대를 부숴놨으니까.
Otherwise I should already
have beaten you
for breaking my bed.
- 날 한번 때렸어요.
- 맞아, 미안해.
You hit me once.
Yes, and I'm sorry.
나 보다 엄마를 더 사랑했어요.
You love my mother
more than me.
아저씨 보다는 그런 건
내가 더 잘알아요.
I know about those
things better than you.
아마 여자였으면
그런 남자들 일을 잘 알거예요.
You always know those
things about men
when you're a woman.
그렇지 않은 남자도 있어.
Some men are different.
난 그렇지 않아.
I'm different.
음...
Well...
나도 똑같을지도 모르지...
...maybe not after all,
because...
난 전부 네것이야, 바이올렛.
I'm all yours, Violet.
전부 내것?
All mine?
그래.
Yes.
한 번 사랑하고,
두 번 사랑하고,
I love you once,
I love you twice,
당신을 콩과,
쌀알 수만큼 사랑해요.
I love you more
than beans and rice.
정말 행복하게 해드릴께요.
I'm going to make
you so happy.
아저씬 내 스타일의 남자예요.
정말 그래요.
You're just my kind of man.
You really are.
난 정말 잘해요,
그래요, 쉐리.
I'm really good,
you know, Cherie.
제발 그렇게 말하지 마.
창녀 처럼 말하지 말라구.
Don't talk to me
like that, please.
Don't talk like a whore.
그럼 무슨 말을 하라구요?
And what do you want me
to say?
내 안에 있는 느낌을
말한 것 뿐이고,
I feel something inside me,
so I say it,
당신이 떠날 때면,
날 아프게 해요...
and when you go away,
it hurts me...
바로 여기.
right here.
아마 넌 배가고픈 걸거야.
You're only hungry, perhaps.
근데 창녀가 뭐가 잘못됐는데요?
And what's wrong
with whores anyhow?
우릴 좋아하는줄 알았는데.
I thought you liked us.
모두 나보고 예쁘댔어요.
Everybody says I'm pretty.
나도 조금 지나면
살이 붙을 거예요...
I'm getting to be
filled out soon...
모든 남자들이 날 좋아한다구요.
and all the other men like me.
날 좋아하지 않아요?
Don't you like me?
날 종일 혼자뒀어요.
You left me all alone.
메모를 남겼는데.
I left you a note.
아직 못읽는다구요.
Well, I can't read yet.
선물을 가져왔어.
I brought you a present.
선물? 어디요?
A present? Where?
으!
Ugh!
어딨어요?
Where is it?
예쁘다.
She's beautiful.
왜 인형을 사왔어요?
Why did you buy me a doll?
어린 애들에겐 인형이 있어야잖아.
Every child should have a doll.
내가 어린애예요?
I'm a child to you?
바이올렛.
Violet.
Come out and play with me.
바이올렛!
Violet!
바이올렛?
Violet?
Oh.
바이올렛, 어디 아프니?
Violet, what ails you?
무슨 일이야, 바이올렛?
What's the matter, Violet?
바이올렛, 네게 묻잖아.
Violet, I'm talking to you.
머리가 깨질 것 같아.
I've got such
a splittin' headache.
넌 정말 이기적이야, 바이올렛.
You're so selfish, Violet.
이건 불공평해.
It's just not fair.
나만 빼고 다른 사람들은
자기가 원하는 것을 한다구.
People get to do
what they want except me.
바이올렛, 앞쪽 방 테이블 위에 둔
병들을 네가 가져갔니?
Violet, did you
take those bottles
that I left on the table
in the front room?
유리 마개 달린거 말예요?
The ones
with the glass stoppers?
그래.
Yes.
네, 그걸 가지고 놀았어요.
Yes. I was playing
with them.
그 안에 든 것을 어떻게 했는데?
Well, what did you do
with what was inside of them?
쏫아 버렸는데요.
Well, I poured it out.
이런, 바이올렛,
그건 질산은이야.
My God, Violet,
that's silver nitrate.
사진을 뽑는데 쓰는 거라구.
I use it for my photographs.
대체 왜그런 짓을 한거야?
Whatever made you do
such a thing?
냄새가 안좋았어요.
Well, it smelled so bad.
네가 아무 생각없이 한 짓 때문에,
Because of your
thoughtlessness,
그걸 구하러
시내까지 다녀와야 되잖아.
I have to go
all the way uptown
to replace those chemicals.
게다가 아주 비싸단 말야.
And they're very expensive.
왜 울어?
Why are you crying?
즐거움을 위해서.
For joy.
또 날 즐겁게 하려구요.
And to amuse myself.
같이 갈래?
You want to come with me?
싫어!
No!
그게 뭐예요?
What are those?
- 뭐가 뭐야?
- 그 옷 말예요.
What are what?
Those clothes.
아, 이거?
파자마지.
Oh, these?
These are pajamas.
여태 파자마를 본 적 없다고
말하려는 건 아니겠지?
You aren't going to tell me
you've never in your life
seen pajamas?
아니, 그런 옷을
입은 것은 처음 봐요.
No john I ever saw
wore anything like that.
여기 누워있기 지쳤어요.
I'm tired of lying here.
조용히 1 초만 더 있었더라면,
사진을 찍었을 텐데.
If you would have stayed quiet
for one second more,
I would have had it.
항상 1 초만 더라잖아요,
It's always one second more
그리고 왜 내 사진을
찍고 또 찍는거예요?
with you,
and why do you want
to take my picture
again and again and again?
나도 꼬맹이하고
이러는 데에 지쳤어.
I'm tired of having
to deal with a child.
나도 여기 있으면서 아저씨가
소리 지르는거 들을 필요 없어.
I don't have
to stay here
and listen to you yell at me.
난 떠날거야.
이젠 어떤 사람 사진도 못찍게 될거야.
Well, I'm leaving.
And you won't have anyone
to photograph anymore.
이따위로 내게 보답하는거야?
So this is how
you would repay me?
뭐에 대한 보답?
무슨 보답?
Repay you for what?
For what?
아저씨에게 신세진거
하나도 없다구.
I don't owe you
anything at all.
나가!
Get out!
나가, 바이올렛,
널 죽이기 전에.
Get out, Violet,
before I kill you.
내 사진을 더 깨트렸다가는....
If you destroy any more
of my pictures.
그 사진에 누가 관심을 가지는데?
Who cares about your pictures?
누가 그걸 사지?
아무도 안사.
Who buys them?
No one.
회개하라, 죄인들이여.
Repent, sinners.
죄인들이여!
Sinners!
기도하라! 기도하라!
Pray! Pray!
이 지독한 전염병 구덩이에는
죽음과 파멸의 천사 1,500 이 살고있어요.
These freaking pest holes
are inhabited by 1,500 angels
of death and damnation.
네 마녀가 호사스런 죄의 궁전에서
순결한 소녀의미덕을 위태롭게하지요.
Four hags
in palatial palaces of guilt
imperil the virtue
of every innocent girl.
건장한 사내와 연약한 여자의 나약함을 어떻게 할 수 있을까요?
And what, dearly beloved,
can we do about the weakness
of lusting men and soft women?
타락과...
Corrupting...
바이올렛,
어디갔었어?
Violet, where you been?
여기서 빠져나가는게 좋겠다.
We better get out of here.
잡히게되면,
"선한 목자의 집"으로 가게 될거야.
If they catch us, we'll go
to the Home for Good Shepherds.
형재 자매들이여,
연합하십시오!
Brothers and sisters, unite!
멍청한 청교도들.
Stupid puritans.
넬이 그러는데 얼쩡거리러 온
호색한들 일 뿐이랬어.
Nell says it's just horny men
who come around to snoop.
이번에는 정말 일을 내려나봐.
Well, this time,
they're really going to do it.
마마 모스베가 그러는데
모두 문을 닫아야 할거랬어.
Mama Mosebery says
everything will be closed down.
- 그럼 어떻게 되는데?
- 나도 몰라.
So what if they do?
I don't know.
- 난 어떻게 될까?
- 내 기둥서방이 되면 돼.
What'll become of me?
You can be my fancy man.
미쳤나봐.
She's gone mad.
말했잖아.
마담 넬 까지 미쳤어.
I told you.
Even Madame Nell.
사악한 눈이
우리 모두를 지켜봐.
The evil eye is on us all.
보라구.
Look.
소금 고리야.
Circles of salt.
누가 마법을 걸었군요.
Somebody put a spell on you.
올라 메, 이 성수로 주방하고
마담 넬 방을 씼어내.
Ola Mae, take this holy water
and wash the kitchen
and Miss Nell's room.
로마 시대...
In Rome...
이런 시기에...
times like these...
야만인들이 침입해왔지.
barbarians came.
오, 정말 그랬어.
Oh, did they.
그런 일은 계속되고
반복된다구.
It goes on
and on.
초인종 소리를 들었는데.
모두 어딜 간거야?
I heard the doorbell.
Where is everybody?
죽음이 그들을 떠나게 했어요.
Death is keeping them away.
죽기 위해선 이유가 있어야해.
그럴싸한 이유.
There are reasons for death.
Good reasons.
오, 그런 말 말아요.
제발.. 그만 두실래요?
Oh, stop talking.
Would you... stop it?
실례해요.
Excuse me.
버릇없는 놈,
행동거지 하고는.
Dirty roughnecks
with their rotten manners.
버릇없는 놈,
행동거지 하고는.
Dirty roughnecks with
their rotten manners.
네 맘이 바뀔지 모르니까
역에서 1 시간 동안 기다릴께.
We'll be at the station
for an hour,
if you change your mind.
안녕.
Bye.
조니, 가자.
Come on, Joanie, let's go.
어차피 형편없는 피아노였어.
Terrible piano anyhow.
너 참 예쁘구나.
Oh, you look so fine.
바이올렛, 노처녀들,
우린 시카고로 갈거야.
Violet, old gal,
we'll go to Chicago.
시카고는 돈이 넘쳐나는 도시라구.
Chicago is the money town.
우린 거기서 전성기를 보낼거야.
Oh, we'll have ourselves
a time there.
뉴 올리스 중앙역에서
북행 열차를 탈거야.
Take the northbound
New Orleans Central.
헤이.
Hey.
조심해요.
섬세한 물건이라구요.
Careful now.
These are delicate things.
어디로 가는거니, 바이올렛?
네 형편없는 엄마는 어딨어?
Where are you going, Violet?
Where's that no-good mother
of yours?
- 엄마가 보낸 엽서와 편지가 있어.
- 발신지 주소도 없는거, 어?
I gots a postcard from her,
and a letter.
With no return address, huh?
- 엄마 얘기 하지마요.
- 어이구, 가슴이 찢어지네.
Don't talk about her.
Aw, you're breakin' my heart.
- 파파, 여기서 뭐하는거예요?
- 너와 결혼할거야.
Papa, what are you doing here?
I'm going to marry you.
언니들에게 물어봐도 돼요?
Can I ask all the girls?
근데 안토니아랑 저스틴은 떠났어요,
오데뜨와 조세핀두요.
But Antonia and Justine
have gone,
and-and Odette and Josephine.
- 데리러 가도 돼요?
- 당연하지.
Can we go get them?
Of course.
근데, 뭘 입죠?
Well, what'll I wear?
네가 원하는 옷으로 뭐든 입어도 돼,
나와 결혼만 한다면 말야.
You can wear whatever
your heart desires,
just as long as
you do it with me.
아버지는 누군지 모르고,
엄머니는 얘를 버렸어요.
Her father unknown,
and the mother
deserted the child.
엄마 이름은 힐드가예요,
힐드가 마... M-A-R-R.
My mama's name
was Hildegarde,
Hildegarde Marr... M-A-R-R.
엄마가 코카시안(백인)
이었나, 아니었나?
And she was Caucasian or other?
창녀였어요, 신부님.
She was a whore, Father.
하느님께서 맺은 인연을
사람이 깨지 못할지니라.
Those whom God has united,
let no man put asunder.
성부와 성자와 성령의 이름으로
In nomine patri et filii
et spritus sanctus.
신부에게 키스하십시오.
You may kiss the bride.
# 어디 갔었지, 빌리 보이?
Oh, where have you been,
Billy Boy, Billy Boy?
# 어디 갔었어, 멋쟁이 빌리?
Oh, where have you been,
charming Billy?
# 아내를 보러 갔었지,
# 내 인생에 가장 사랑스러운 여인
Oh, I've been to see my wife,
she's the darling of my life
# 너무 어려서 엄마를 못떠난다네
She's a young thing
and cannot leave her mother
# 아내가 체리파이는 만들줄 알아,
# 빌리 보이, 빌리, 보이?
Can she bake a cherry pie,
Billy Boy, Billy Boy?
# 체리 파이는 만들줄 아냐구,
# 멋쟁이 빌리야?
Can she bake a cherry pie,
charming Billy?
# 그야 물론 만들줄 알지
# 눈 깜짝할 사이에
She can bake a cherry pie
quick as you can wink your eye
# 너무 어려서 엄마를 떠날수 없어.
She's a young thing
and cannot leave her mother.
파파, 저기 좋은 자리가 있어,
옆으로 대라구요.
Papa, there's a good spot
over there... pull over.
아냐, 더 돌아봐, 파파.
아까 거기가 더 좋았어.
Hell, no, turn around, Papa.
The other place was better.
- 아냐! 보라구... 거기 말야!
- 앉아!
No! Come on... over here!
Sit down!
이런...
Well...
모두 내려서 밀어야겠는데.
We'll just have
to get out and push.
하지만 시카고에 가려고
새 드레스를 입었는걸.
But I am wearing my new dress
for Chicago.
전부 새 드레스를 입었어,
멍청한 지지배야.
We're all wearing
our new dresses, you damn fool.
그럼 옷일랑 벗어버리고
이 일을 축하하자구.
Well, let's get
our damn clothes off
and celebrate this thing.
- 나 굴 좀 더줘.
- 쏘스가 더 필요한 사람?
Pass me some more oysters.
Anyone want some of this sauce?
Oh, yeah.
이거 먹어봐, 오데뜨.
Try this, Odette.
- 파파, 어서와서 먹어요.
- 그래, 갈께.
Papa, come eat.
Yes, I'm coming.
우! 저것 좀 봐!
Ooh, look at that one!
파파, 아무것도 안먹었잖아요.
자, 먹어요.
Papa, you didn't
eat anything before.
Now, eat.
어떻게 남자는 한명에
여자기 이렇게 많지?
How come one man
got so many women?
오늘 막 결혼했어요.
He just got married today.
누구랑 결혼했는지 맞춰봐요?
And guess who he married?
알겠어요?
Guess?
그건 상관없어,
Well, it doesn't matter,
결혼식 날 이렇게
운좋은 놈은 처음봤으니까.
'cause he's the luckiest
son of a bitch
I ever seen on a wedding day.
종은 왜 울려?
필요한 것은 다 있는데.
Why are you ringing?
You have everything you need.
브랜디를 넣은 코코아 마시고 싶어요.
오늘은 몸이 안좋다구요.
I want some hot chocolate
with brandy in it.
I feel poorly today.
아, 유감이네.
이번 엔 왜그러는데?
Oh, I'm sorry.
What is it this time?
- 알잖아요.
- 당연히 알지. 잊어버렸지만..
Oh, you know.
Oh, yes, of course.
I forgot.
오늘은 하루 종~일 잘거예요.
I'm going to sleep
all day today.
그게 지난 2주 동안 한 것과
뭐가 다른데?
Well, how is that any different
from the last two weeks?
코코아좀 가져다 줘.
Get me some cocoa.
브랜디도.
And the bottle of brandy.
말야... 그러니까,
언니들이 가르쳐줬어...
Do you... I mean,
did the girls teach you...
미리 예방 하는거 말야...
임신 되는걸?
how to prevent yourself
from... becoming with child?
그렇게 할 수 있는거냐구?
I mean,
did you know you can?
그런 얘기 하지 말아요.
Don't tell me about that.
나도 다 아는 얘기
하지 말라구요.
Don't tell me
about the things I know.
고집쟁이 아가씨는
맛있는 스프 못만들어.
Hard-headed bird
don't make good soup.
올라 매가 항상 내게 그랬어요.
That's what Ola Mae
used to say about me.
나도 알아.
I know.
바이올렛?
Violet?
엄마?
Mama?
그래, 엄마야!
Yes, it's Mama!
오, 바이올렛,
내 새끼, 내 사랑!
Oh, Violet, my baby, my darling!
이렇게 자랐다니.
Look at the way you've grown.
널 찾으러 안다닌 데가 없어.
We have been looking
everywhere for you.
Here we go.
아저씨께 다 얘기 했어, 바이올렛,
널 꼭 데려와야 한다고 하셨어.
I told him
all about you, Violet,
and he insisted that
we come and get you.
엄마에게서 좋은 냄새가 나.
You smell good, Mama.
세인트 루이스에
크고 멋진 집이 있어.
We've got a big, beautiful house
in St. Louis.
풀러 씨는
포장공사 청부 사업을 하셔.
Mr. Fuller,
he's a pavement contractor.
말야, 세인트 루이스의
거의 모든 거리를 포장했단다.
You know, he's paved almost
every street in St. Louis.
그리고 네가 우리와
집에 오길 바라셔.
And he wants you
to come home with us.
하지만 난 여기 살아.
But I live here.
나와 파파는,
파파와 난 결혼했어.
I and Papa,
Papa and I are married now.
퓰러 부인,
잘 지내시는걸 보니 정말 기쁘네요.
Mrs. Fuller,
I'm so glad to see
you are doing so well.
리틀 윌두요.
And little Will.
퓰러씨와 난
당신과 아무 상관 없어요, 벨라크 씨.
Mr. Fuller and I want nothing
to do with you, Mr. Bellocq.
당신과 내 딸을 찾으러
끔찍한 곳 까지 다녀야 했다구요.
We had to go
to some-some awful places
to find out about you
and my daughter.
해티, 우린 결혼한 사이예요,
이러지 말야요.
Hattie, we're married now,
so stop this.
내 허락 없이는 불법이예요.
It is not legal
without my consent.
퓰러 씨가 이미 다 알아봤어요.
Mr. Fuller has
already seen to that.
당신이 버렸잖소.
무자비하게 대하려는 것은 아니지만...
You deserted the child.
I don't mean
to be cruel, but...
- 감히 어떻게 그런 말을?!
- 자, 미스터 발라크, 정신차려요.
- How dare you say that?!
- Now, Mr. Bellocq,
be sensible.
난 바이올렛을 학교에 보내고 싶소,
얘는... 제대로 자라야 해요.
Now, I want
to send Violet to school,
and she has to be...
raised right.
여러 면으로 보더라도, 우리는
오만하게 행동할 어떤 권리도 없어요.
Now, I know
that in a lot of ways
we've got no right
to get up on a high horse.
현재는 퓰러 부인은
과거를 극복했어요,
But now, Mrs. Fuller
has overcome her past,
바이올렛도
그러길 바라고 있구요.
and she wants the same
for Violet.
얘를 데려갈 수 없어!
Well, you cannot take her!
얘 없이는 못산다구...
그래서야.
I can't live without her...
that's all.
파파, 같이 가면 되잖아요.
Papa, you can come with us.
어서, 바이올렛.
Come on, Violet.
짐은 쌀 필요 없어.
You don't need to pack.
기차 기다릴동안 카날 스트리트에서
네게 필요한 것을 사줄께.
We'll get you whatever you need
on Canal Street
while we're waiting
for the train.
다 같이 가면 안돼요?
Can't we all go?
준비 됐어?
You ready?
- 어-허. 잠깐만.
- 자, 훨씬 낫네.
Uh-huh. Just a minute.
There, now, that's better.
이제 됐군.
Now we're ready.
- 자, 아빠를 봐.
- 오케이, 가까이 서봐.
Come on, look at Papa.
Okay, move in closer.
좋아.
Good.
한장 더 찍자구.
Now let's get one more.
오케이.
Okay.
왜 그러는 거야, 아가야?
What's the matter, honey?
괜찮아?
Is he okay?
아니, 괜찮아요.
No, he's fine.
더 찍을 거예요?
Do you wanna take any more?
# 한글화 : 태름아버지(200701) #
06, 12, 29, 유명을 달리하신
시네스트 도체님께 이 자막을 바칩니다.
▶◀ 삼가 고인의 명복을 빕니다 ▶◀